CAIO VINÍCIUS

+55 (86) 99963-2527 | devcaioviniciusml@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/caioviniciusml/ | GitHub

ABOUT ME

I have solid knowledge and experience in technologies and frameworks focused on the design and development of web applications, having worked throughout all stages of the development process, from system design and development until the deployment and maintenance.

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Next.js | Postcss | Sass | Tailwind | Bootstrap | UI/UX | Figma | Node.js | Express.js | Nest.js | Git | CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Loading Desenvolvimento Jr

Front-End Software Engineer

Nov, 2023 - Present

- Integrated the development team responsible for revitalizing the department, increasing the number of solutions delivered by up to 4 times in recent years, ensuring a continuous delivery flow.
- Led the development of the company's largest success story, the ERP system for Innovale Jr, a consulting firm serving over 20 businesses in Ceará, where I was responsible for creating the application's website and integrating it with the system's API.
- Developed and implemented solutions to meet the needs of at least 4 companies from different sectors in the State of Ceará, working from modeling to deployment and maintenance.
- Took responsibility for code reviews, ensuring high-quality products were delivered, along with optimized SEO to increase visibility and conversion rates for clients.
- **Tech Stack:** HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Next.js | Tailwind | Shadon | UI/UX | Figma | Git | CI/CD

Freelancer

Front-End Software Engineer

Oct, 2024 - Present

- Worked on the development of websites for client acquisition, personal portfolios, and product/event promotion, leading to a significant increase in conversion rates.
- Developed a lead capture page website for an online education platform, reaching over 1,200 visits in just 2 weeks. The campaign achieved over 25% conversion rate, surpassing all previous campaigns, including doubling the results of a campaign held in 2024.
- Delivered applications that provided clients greater visibility and efficiency in digital campaigns, both with high quality and SEO optimized, receiving a score of 100 in tests conducted by "PageSpeed Insights".
- Responsible for integrating traffic monitoring tools like Meta Pixel, enabling detailed and strategic tracking of traffic and user behavior.
- **Tech Stack:** HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Next.js | Tailwind | Bootstrap | Shadcn | UI/UX | Figma | Git | CI/CD

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

Federal University of Ceará - UFC

May, 2021 - Present

LANGUAGES

English - Advanced/Full professional proficiency (C1) - <u>EF Set Certificate</u> Portuguese - Native